そんなところだな。
That's about it...
Scouting complete.
偵察終了！
いつもどおり 異常なしだ。
Same as usual,
nothing suspicious.
今日も いい天気だな。
It's another nice day.
Granny, hurry! Hurry!
おばあちゃ～ん！
早く 早く！
これこれ！
そんなに急ぐでないよ。
Now, now. Don't be so hasty.
(ウドン)あ～ん！
A stick of this after a mission...
任務のあとの
この一本のために➡
This is what I live for.
生きてるんだな～。
(モエギ)はぁ…。
(コテツ)さぁ
さっさと選んでもらおうか。
C'mon, hurry and pick a card.
う～ん…。
《白眼！》
Byakugan!
H-Hey! No fair!
おいっ！ なんだよ！
ゲームに白眼は反則だろうが！
You can't use Byakugan
in a game!
Well, I guess I'll start on
the next report that's due.
さてと 定時報告書でも書くかな。
あっ！
Is he from... the Akatsuki?!
《コイツ 暁か！》
Right! Must report this
to Hokage-sama!
《わかった！ 火影様に連絡だな》
わぁ～っ!!
What?!
なにっ!?
うっ！
(天道)いよいよだ。
The time has come.
what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Assault on the Leaf Village!
"Cipher Division"
Jiraiya-sama sent back three
sources of information...
(シカマル)自来也様が持ち帰った
３つの情報…。
Namely, a ninja from
the Hidden Rain...
(シホ)ぶっちゃけ
雨隠れの忍。 ペインの遺体。
Pain's corpse... and...
そして この暗号ですね。
this secret message.
Knowing Inoichi in
the Intel Division,
情報部のいのいちさんなら
すぐにも雨隠れの忍から➡
he'll be able to get
some kind of information
out of the Hidden Rain ninja.
なんらかの情報を
引き出してくれるだろう。
Shizune-senpai has put top priority
(サクラ)ペインの遺体の検死も➡
シズネ先輩が
最優先でやってるところよ。
on the autopsy of Pain's corpse.
She's sure to learn something too.
こっちも間違いないわ。
And this message we decoded
with help from Naruto...
そして ナルト君からの情報で
解けた この暗号。
「ホンモノハ イナイ」ですね。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
We'll have to take all
this information
オレたちは
これから得られる情報の中から➡
and figure out the mystery behind
this guy named Pain.
ペインとかって野郎の謎に
迫らなきゃならねえ。
The mystery of someone who
could even take down Jiraiya-sama.
自来也様ですら
やられちまうような連中の➡
謎ってやつをよ…。
"Hidden Leaf Intel Division"
A genjutsu block...
(いのいち)幻術プロテクトか。
I'm going to take a peek into your mind.
心の中➡
のぞかせてもらうとしよう。
So many genjutsu blocks...
《これほどの幻術プロテクトを…。
No wonder truth serum
didn't work on him.
どおりで
自白剤が効かないわけだな》
How did it go?
(イビキ)どうでした？
It's no use...
ダメだ。 誰かが
頭の中にプロテクトをかけている。
Someone's placed blocks
inside his mind.
It's going to be difficult to
navigate past them.
これを潜り抜けるのは 難しいな。
おそらく ペインとかいうヤツの
術か何かでしょう。
It's probably some jutsu placed
on him by the one named Pain.
Please be careful, Inoichi-san.
気をつけてください
いのいちさん。
There may be genjutsu traps
set in there as well.
幻術トラップが
仕掛けてあるかもしれません。
Yes, I'm aware of that.
ああ わかってる。
AUTOPSY ROOM 3
SHIZUNE
OYONE
KUMADORI
These black rods, which
were embedded in the corpse...
《シズネ : 遺体に埋め込まれた
この黒い棒は➡
Could they be a special feature
of these men known as Pain?
ペインとよばれる者たちの特徴》
Why did they embed this
into the body?
《なぜ彼らは これを
体に埋め込んでいたのか？
I must learn more about
検死の前に この金属の特性を
知る必要がある》
the properties of this metal
before the autopsy.
"CIPHER DIVISION"
(シカマル)暗号の 「ホンモノハ イナイ」。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
それなら そのペインとかっていう
６人は幻術で➡
Maybe the six Pains were genjutsu...
A jutsu created by the female
Akatsuki member
もう１人いたっていう
女の暁の 術かもな。
who was also said to be present.
And she's the one who physically
attacked Jiraiya-sama
そいつが陰から
物理的攻撃で自来也様を…。
from the shadows.
No... That's hard to imagine.
いや そうは考えにくいわ。
フカサク様が言うには➡
According to Fukasaku-sama,
Jiraiya-sama died from being
stabbed by real weapons
自来也様は 実際には➡
その６人に 武器で刺されて
亡くなられたそうよ。
wielded by all six of them.
Well, he took down three of them,
まあ そのペインを３人倒したけど➡
but they supposedly
resurrected themselves...
生き返ったっていうし…。
It does sound like some
unbelievable genjutsu.
信じがたい幻術のような話だけど。
Common sense has no meaning
when it comes to the Akatsuki.
暁に 常識は通じねえよ。
There have been others
who were immortal.
不死のヤツらまで いたんだからな。
In any case, let's keep hypothesizing
all possible scenarios
とにかく
他の情報が出てくるまで➡
ある程度のパターンを できるだけ
推測しておきましょう。
until we get reports from the others.
だな。
You're right.
Let's at least be a little closer
to solving Pain's mystery
ナルトが修業から
帰ってくるまでに➡
by the time Naruto returns
from his training.
少しでも ペインの
謎に近づきましょう。
(シマ)どれ。
Well then...
I'm going to procure us
some fresh ingredients.
ほんなら新鮮な食材を
調達してくるけんな。
Not more of that gross stuff...
Aw man...
《また グロい系かな。
いやだなぁ…》
Ma! Make sure you get
some stamina-building stuff!
母ちゃん 精のつくやつ 頼んだで。
You are able to mold
Sage Jutsu chakra
仙術チャクラも
練れるようになったし➡
and have pretty much mastered
Frog Kumite and Sage Techniques.
蛙組手も仙法も
ある程度 マスターした。
ここで 最後に
ひと言 言うことがある。
Now I have one final thing
to say to you.
Wh-What is it?
You're suddenly so serious.
な… なに なに？
かしこまっちゃってさ。
Well... It's about the risks of
using Sage Mode.
それはな 仙人モードの
リスクについてじゃ。
リスク？
Risks?
Yes... Once you fully grasp
the risks involved,
そうじゃ そのリスクを
ちゃんと把握できてこそ➡
then you can use Sage Mode
to its fullest extent!
仙人モードが最大限に活かされる！
So, what are the risks?
う～ん… で そのリスクって？
First, as you're probably aware,
まずは ナルトちゃんも
わかっとるとは思うが➡
you can't maintain
Sage Mode for too long.
仙人モードは そう長く持続せん。
もって ５分じゃ。
Maybe five minutes at most.
それから 仙人モードになるための
自然エネルギーを集めるには➡
Also, to amass the Nature Energy
necessary to enter Sage Mode,
you must follow the principle
of staying still.
動くな が基本じゃ。
Thus, it cannot be used
once you begin battle.
それゆえ 戦闘に入ってからは
まず使えん。
For when you are still,
動かんかったら
敵の格好の的じゃけんの。
you become an easy target
for your enemy.
Ow!
((イッテ～！))
I see...
なるほど。
じゃろ？
Right?
仙人モードになれるのは➡
So the only time you can go
into Sage Mode is
when you've got plenty
of comrades around you
仲間が たくさんおって
己が フリーになれる時だけじゃ。
that can free you up.
If you are alone,
but must go into Sage Mode,
どうしても １人の時に
仙人モードにならにゃいけん時は➡
withdraw from the battle momentarily
and gather Nature Energy.
いったん戦闘から離脱して
自然エネルギーを集めるしかない。
What?! Then Sage Mode is useless!
ああっ 使えねえじゃん 仙人モード！
じゃあ 今まで何のために…。
So what was all this training for?!
Don't be so disappointed.
そう がっかりするな。
That is why I am here,
to alleviate that risk.
そこで そのリスクを補うために
わしがおるんじゃ。
What do you mean?
それって どういうこと？
If you and I merge our bodies,
it'll be fine!
わしとナルトちゃんが
体を融合すれば➡
それで オーケーじゃ。
No!!
ギャア～！
When I say merge,
融合いうても 背中や肩に➡
it simply means to be lightly
attached to your shoulder or back.
軽く くっつく程度の
融合じゃけんの。
Oh, that's all...
な なんだ… でも なんで
融合すれば オーケーなんだってばよ？
But how does merging
make things fine?
Simply put, it's to split
the roles of stillness and action.
簡単に言えば 静と動の
役割分担をするためじゃ。
When one is moving,
片方が動いとる時は
片方が止まって➡
the other stays still and
gathers Nature Energy.
自然エネルギーを取り込む。
In Jiraiya-chan's case,
the final form of his Sage Mode
自来也ちゃんも わしら夫婦を
両肩に乗っけた状態が➡
had Ma and me both
riding his shoulders.
仙人モード最終形態じゃった。
I see... I get it now...
なるほど そういうことか。
Don't you worry, Naruto-chan!
ま 心配するな ナルトちゃんよ。
Okay!
オッケー！
ここで陽動と探索の
二手に分かれる。
From here on,
we'll be splitting into two teams:
diversion and search.
確認をしておく。
I'll go over it again.
Diversion will be made up
of Shurado, Chikushodo, and Gakido.
陽動は修羅道 畜生道 餓鬼道。
探索は天道➡
Search will be Tendo,
Ningendo, and Jigokudo.
人間道 地獄道でいく。
小南 お前は探索側だ。
(小南)わかってるわ。
Konan, you're with the search team.
I know.
(天道)木ノ葉は
里の地中と上空を含め➡
The Hidden Leaf Village...
is surrounded by
a spherical barrier that
球状の結界を張っている。
includes underground
and aerial coverage.
無断で侵入した人間は➡
Which means anyone
who enters without permission
すぐ感知される仕組み
ということね。
is detected immediately.
作戦どおり畜生道を
木ノ葉上空へ投げ込む。
As planned,
we will launch Chikushodo
into the Hidden Leaf's aerial space.
敵に こっちの人数を誤認させて
かく乱する。
We will confuse the enemy
by not giving them an accurate count.
畜生道からの口寄せを待て。
Wait for Chikushodo's summoning.
イタチと鬼鮫は
簡単に入り込んだらしいけど。
I was told Itachi and Kisame
infiltrated easily.
イタチは木ノ葉の暗部だった男だ。
Itachi once belonged to
the Leaf's Anbu Black Ops.
結界を通り抜ける暗号を
知っていた。
He knew the password
to get through the barrier.
オレにはオレのやり方がある。
I have my own way of doing things.
ここより世界に痛みを。
Starting here,
the world shall know pain...
侵入者だ！
An intruder!
目標は１人 西口イのＢ地点。
Single target, west gate, sector I-B
ねぇ 早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
Yes, I'm coming dear.
ごっそ～さん。
ごちそうさま。
Thanks for the food!
Yes, thank you!
散！
Disperse!
何だ？
What is that?
ぐわぁっ！
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
オレの火遁が効かない！
My Fire Style has no effect!
こうあちこちで…
いったい どうなってる!?
It's all over the place! What's going on?!
侵入者は１人じゃなかったのか？
I thought there was just one intruder!
すぐに白眼で確認します！
I'll confirm with the Byakugan
right away!
結界班だけでは間に合わん！
This is beyond the scope
of just the Barrier Corps!
他の部隊に連絡して
救援を要請しろ！
Contact other troops and
request backup! Hurry!
急げ！
はっ！
Right!
オレは火影様に連絡に行く！
I'll go notify Hokage-sama!
九尾の情報は 持っていないか。
He holds no information
on the Nine-Tails.
うずまきナルトは どこだ？
Where is Naruto Uzumaki?
コイツも知らんか。
He doesn't know either...
急に チャクラの計器が反応して
黒い棒が加熱したから➡
The chakra meter shot up suddenly
and the black rod began warming up,
おかしいと思ったんだ。
so I thought it was strange.
These are demodulators for
receiving high frequency chakra waves.
これ 高周波チャクラを受ける
復調装置だったんだ。
復調装置…
つまり なんです？
Demodulator?
Which means what?
つまり これは
チャクラの受信機ってこと。
In other words,
they're chakra receivers!
今 まさに受信してる。
And, it's receiving
at this very moment!
受信機？ どういうことです？
Receiver? What do you mean?
つまり
これが受信機ってことは…。
If this is a receiver...
っと そんな説明してるより
すぐに綱手様に連絡しなきゃ。
I don't have time to explain.
I have to notify Tsunade-sama
immediately...
な なんだ？
What was that?
これって！
行くぞ！
What's that?
Let's go!
見つけた！
Found it!
(イノ)なんなの？ あっ！
What was that?
チョウジ 私は情報部に連絡を。
(チョウジ)うん。
Choji! I'll notify the Intel Division.
Right!
《ボクは 父ちゃんのところへ》
I have to get to Pa!
お父さん 里が！
Father! The village is...
うわぁ～！
なんだ!?
あっ！
逃げろ！
Run!
たみちゃん。
Tami-chan!
しゃんなろ～！
Shannaro!
大丈夫？
Are you all right?!
う うん。
ありがとうございます。
U-Uh-huh.
Th-Thank you so much!
うっ！
ムカデが倒れている。
あの子がやってくれたようだ。
The centipede is down...
Seems that girl did it.
よかった そんなに傷は
深くないわね。
Thank goodness!
Your wound is not too deep.
ありがとう。
Thank you...
(イルカ)サクラ！
Sakura!
大丈夫か？
イルカ先生。
Are you all right?
Iruka-sensei...
いったい
何が起こってるんですか？
Just what's going on?
わからん …が 何者かが
木ノ葉に攻めてきた。
I don't know.
But someone is attacking
the Leaf Village!
状況は 綱手様に
すでに連絡した。
The situation has been
reported to Tsunade-sama.
すぐにも
警報が発令されるだろう。
The alarm should sound soon.
里に 直接 攻めてくるなんて。
The village is under direct attack?
いったい何者が？
Who would do such a thing?
いくぞ イルカ。
ああ。
Let's go, Iruka!
Right!
サクラは 急いで病院へ行って
ケガ人を見てくれ。
Sakura, hurry to the hospital
and tend to the wounded.
病院には たくさんのケガ人がいる。
はい。
It's full of injured people.
Yes, sir!
《まさか！》
It can't be...
お姉ちゃん。
Miss...
大丈夫 私たちには
火影様がいるでしょ。
It's going to be all right!
We have the Hokage-sama
on our side!
うん。
Uh-huh!
結界班より報告。
Barrier Corps reporting!
侵入者は 木ノ葉上空より潜入。
An intruder entered Hidden
Leaf Village through our air space.
結界反応は単騎。
Our sensors picked up
a single target.
ですが 反応直後より
複数の襲撃を確認しました。
But shortly after detection,
several attacks were confirmed.
分析班より報告。
Analysis Corps reporting!
敵戦力 およそ三個大隊。
Enemy strength estimated
as three battalions in size!
《綱手 : これほどの戦力を
悟られることなく運用できる敵。
A foe capable of organizing
this much military power unnoticed...
やはり…》
It must be...
報告 侵入者の目撃情報。
Reporting! I have a witness report
on the intruder!
黒衣に朱色の雲模様。
He wore black with
a red cloud pattern.
《暁 ついに来たか》
The Akatsuki...
So they've finally come.
((予言の子は
あの子であってほしいと➡
I can't help but hope that
he is the Child of Prophecy.
そう願わずにはおれんのう。
(自来也ちゃんは すべてを
あの子に託したんじゃからな))
For Jiraiya-chan has entrusted
his all to that child.
非常事態警報を出せ。
Sound the state of emergency alarm.
それから ナルトを呼び戻せ。
And...
Recall Naruto!
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
Next Episode
(ナツ)こいつら…。
(ルーシィ)オラシオンセイス!?
Who do you think you are?!
(ハッピー)だよねぇ。
(グレイ)随分雰囲気違くねえか？
Still treating him like a mere child!
(エルザ)メンバーも違うようだな。
The will of the Hidden Leaf has been passed on,
(ジャックポット)
ヨホホホホ。 ホイ そろった！ 激アツ！
and it's growing!
Naruto strives to surpass Jiraiya this very minute!
まさしく これぞオラシオンセイス。
Just as my grandfather, the First Hokage,
いえいえ…。 新生オラシオンセイスと
お見知りおきください。 ませ！
believed and entrusted the Leaf to you.
(みんな)新生オラシオンセイス!?
It is now your turn to believe and entrust to the next generation!
Power to Believe
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Power to Believe"